Guide to the Center for Documentary Studies student projects collection, 1980-2011 and undated RL.01266
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Center for Documentary Studies student projects collection
1980-2011 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Duke University. Center for Documentary Studies
RL.01266
40 Linear Feet
The Center for Documentary Studies at Duke University teaches, engages in, and presents documentary work grounded in collaborative partnerships and extended fieldwork that uses photography, film/video, audio, and narrative writing to capture and convey contemporary memory, life, and culture. The collection houses work created by students enrolled in documentary studies courses at Duke University in Durham, North Carolina, and the University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill (UNC), sponsored by the Center for Documentary Studies at Duke. The student projects focus primarily on exploring and documenting the social lives and experiences of people living in and around rural and urban areas of Durham, Chatham, and Orange counties, North Carolina, through photography or oral history. Subjects include but are not limited to local school environments; churches and religious life; ethnic communities and neighborhoods; war veterans; the 9/11 attacks; the labor and civil rights movements as experienced by local individuals; students at Duke University; farmers and their families; immigrant life; migrant workers; beauty pageants; local music scenes; and the built environment and culture of North Carolina towns, and cities. Audiovisual materials include sound recordings and moving images, and may require reformatting before contents can be accessed. Acquired by the Archive of Documentary Arts at Duke University.
Approx. 10,00 Items
Access Restrictions
Portions of the collection are restricted.
Original audiovisual and electronic media are closed to use. Use of these materials may require production of listening or viewing copies.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. There may be a 48-hour delay in obtaining these materials.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Collection Overview
Collection houses photographs, interviews, essays, and other documentary works created by students enrolled in courses or thesis projects on documentary studies at Duke University in Durham, North Carolina, and the University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill (UNC), from 1980 to 2011. Most of the student projects focus on the social life and customs of persons living in and around Durham, Chatham, and Orange counties, North Carolina. Themes include life in cities and towns, particularly in Durham; rural life; schools and other institutions such as churches and retirement homes, and charitable organizations such as soup kitchens and orphanages; community centers such as stores, daycares, and laundromats; African American communities and neighborhoods, particularly in Durham; beauty pageants; local music; farmers and their families; immigrant life; migrant workers; midwives; the 9/11 attacks in New York City; and Duke University students and campus life. One series of images portrays the Chuck Davis African American Dance Ensemble in Durham. Oral histories of N.C. civil rights and labor activists, American war veterans, and other individuals are associated with certain courses.
The majority of projects focus on Durham area locales, but other cities and towns in N.C. documented include Chapel Hill, Hillsborough, Raleigh, Seagrove, Wanchese, Cane Creek, Oxford, Carrboro, Orange Factory, Rougemont, Saxapahaw, Salisbury, Northside, Corinth, and Cedar Grove. There are a few projects based in Virginia, and summer projects located in Massachusetts, Tennessee, Tel-Aviv, and France.
The collection also includes a few grant-supported projects by professional documentarians Eric Green, Kate Rhodenbaugh, Carolina Wang, and Donna Lennard, and photographic work by Bill Bamberger, a faculty member at Duke.
Black-and-white prints make up the majority of formats, but there are also many slides. The more recent additions increasingly include oral histories on audio cassettes and CD-ROMS and other project-related digital media. These are marked in the folder descriptions. Original audiovisual and electronic media are closed to use and may require the production of use copies before they can be accessed.
The courses were all sponsored by the Center for Documentary Photography, which in 1989 changed its name to the Center for Documentary Studies. Among the faculty teaching courses for the Center for Documentary Studies are noted documentarians Bill Bamberger, John Biewen, David Cecelski, Alex Harris, and Margaret Sartor, some of whom have contributed their own documentary work to the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library.
Acquired as part of the Archive of Documentary Arts at Duke University.
Arrangement note
Project folders are arranged chronologically by year, then by course number and title; within course groupings, student projects are listed in alphabetical order by last name. Some earlier listings do not have an identified course title. Individual projects such as senior year work (sometimes called a "capstone" project) have separate entries within the appropriate year. Titles and captions were created by the documentary authors; bracketed titles have been supplied by library staff.
Related Material
Literacy Through Photography Collection
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University
Chatham County, N.C. -- Pictorial works; Schools -- Durham, N.C. -- Pictorial works; Durham (N.C.) -- Social life and customs; Durham County (N.C.) -- Pictorial works; African Americans -- Durham (N.C.); Agriculture -- North Carolina -- Pictorial works; Migrant workers -- North Carolina -- Pictorial works; Labor unions -- Durham (N.C.); North Carolina -- Social conditions; North Carolina -- Photographs; Durham (N.C.) -- History -- 20th century; Durham (N.C.) -- Buildings, structures, etc. -- Pictorial works; Durham (N.C.) -- Religious life; Durham (N.C.) -- Pictorial works; Civil rights workers -- North Carolina -- Interviews; Country life -- North Carolina -- Pictorial works; Documentary Photography -- North Carolina; Education -- North Carolina; Beauty pageants -- North Carolina -- Pictorial works; Children -- North Carolina -- Pictorial works; City and town life -- Durham, N.C. -- Pictorial works; Slides (photographs); Oral histories (document genre); City and town life -- North Carolina -- Pictorial works; Black-and-white photographs; CD-ROMs; DVDs; Color photographs; Farmers -- North Carolina -- Pictorial works; Labor movement -- North Carolina; Orange County (N.C.) -- Pictorial works; Audiocassettes; Inkjet prints; Gelatin silver prints; Videocassettes; Duke University -- Pictorial works; Duke University. Center for Documentary Studies; Duke University -- Students
- Duke, Fall 1980
  - Anderson, Robert M. and Andrew Charles Lohman, 2 folders (Box 1)
    Scope and Contents note
    "Farm Life." Cane Creek, N.C.
    "Coy Armstrong." Cane Creek, N.C.
  - Hayward, Barbara A. (Box 1)
    "Edward Henegar: Pastor, Blacknall Memorial Presbyterian Church." Durham, N.C.
  - Henderson, James Herschel (Box 1)
    "Methodist Retirement Home." Durham, N.C.
  - Mackey, Eugenie "Gigi" Lewis, Jr. (Box 1)
    "Village Life." Orange Factory, N.C.
  - Miller, Teresa A. (Box 1)
    "Two Homes." Chapel Hill, N.C.
  - Rhodenbaugh, Kathleen Sue (Box 1)
    "Chatham County Adolescent Group Home." Chatham County, N.C.
  - Schwimmer, Krista A. (Box 1)
    "Lucy and Family." Durham, N.C.
  - Smyth, Douglas E. (Box 1)
    "Urban Decay." Salisbury, N.C.
  - Tutterow, Vestal (Box 1)
    "Calvary United Methodist Church." Durham, N.C.
  - Warburg, Jenny (Box 1)
    "West End Community." Durham, N.C.
  - Ward, Eric R. (Box 1)
    "Black Community." Durham, N.C.
  - Weenan, Hugo (Box 1)
- Duke, Spring 1981
  - Alexoff, David L. (Box 2)
    "St. Phillip's Community Kitchen." Durham, N.C.
  - Arapoglou, Laurel M. (Box 2)
    "Granny Midwives." Halifax County, N.C.
  - Bodell, Karstin (Box 2)
    "Hospice." Orange County, N.C.
  - Burkart, Deborah S. (Box 2)
    "Palm Park Apartments Family." Durham, N.C.
  - Cathey, Marcy E. (Box 2)
    "Rockwell Family" Durham, N.C. (?)
  - Dunn, Susanne E. (Box 2)
    "Cedar Terrace Mobile Home Park." Durham, N.C.
  - Fong, Laurence T. (Box 2)
    "Lenox Baker Children's Hospital." Durham, N.C.
  - Gambrell, Sarah Belk (Box 2)
    "Farm Life." Hillsborough, N.C.
  - Horwitz, Kate Lynn (Box 2)
  - Hum, Franklin R., Jr. (Box 2)
    "A Community Working Together. Pittsboro-Bynum Community Center." N. Chatham County, N.C.
  - Kemp, Barbara (Box 2)
    "The Canady Family." Northside, N.C.
  - Klausner, Andrea B. (Box 2)
    "St. Theresa Community." Durham, N.C.
  - Markwordt, Joseph J. (Box 3)
    "Family in East Durham." Durham, N.C.
  - Sartor, Margaret (Box 3)
    "Chapel of the Cross." Chapel Hill, N.C.
  - Schiff, James A. (Box 3)
    "Coca-Cola Bottling Plant." Durham, N.C.
  - Smyth, Douglass Everett (Box 3)
    "A Trailer Park, an Apartment Complex, and a Condominium Development." Durham, N.C.
  - Taylor, Barbara S. (Box 3)
    "Ronald McDonald House." Durham, N.C.
  - Thompson, Mark W. (Box 3)
    "Rural Community." Corinth Community, N.C.
  - Tyler, Virginia L. (Box 3)
    "Community Living Project." Durham, N.C.
- UNC, Spring 1981
  - Baity, Laura Ann (Box 4)
    "Rural Community." Saxapahaw, N.C.
  - Bedford, Deborah (Box 4)
    "A Woman's Life and Work." Chatham County, N.C.
  - Brody, Sharon Jeanne (Box 4)
    "Small Town Life." Pittsboro, N.C.
  - Krogh, Peter H. (Box 4)
    "Small Town Life; Blacks." Gum Springs, N.C.
  - Monath, Robert (Box 4)
    "Latta's Garage." Hillsborough, N.C.
  - Otwell, Elizabeth F. (Box 4)
    "Woodell Family of Pembroke." Pembroke, N.C.
  - Reeves, Carol (Box 4)
    "Trailer Court." Chapel Hill, N.C.
  - Roberts, Ken (Box 4)
    "Residential Community." Sara Lyn, N.C.
  - Sanders, Kim (Box 4)
    "Lendenself Community." Roxboro, N.C.
  - Taylor, Michael Keith (Box 4)
    "Small Town Life." Rock Ridge, N.C.
  - Turner, Joseph L. (Box 4)
    "Family Life." Siler City and Bonlee, N.C.
  - Weaver, Katherine T. (Box 4)
    "Minnis' Grocery Store." Hillsborough, N.C.
  - Worthy, Marion Carter (Box 4)
    "Cole Pottery." Seagrove, N.C.
- Duke, Fall 1981
  - Blatt, Mary Ann (Box 5)
    "Beth-El Synagogue." Durham, N.C.
  - Cocke, Jenny (Box 5)
    "Taing Family, Seng Ung's Family." Durham, N.C.
  - Dworshak, Wendy (Box 5)
    "Neighborhood Grocery Store." Durham, N.C.
  - Eschenberg, Christian (Box 5)
    "Sunnyside Community." Durham, N.C.
  - Futter, Claudia (Box 5)
    "Hickstown." Durham, N.C.
  - Jackson, Donna (Box 5)
    "Greenhouse." Durham, N.C.
  - Kight, Robert (Box 5)
    "Primrose Community." Orange County, N.C.
  - Laitman, Elinor G. (Box 5)
    "Textile Mill." Rocky Mount, N.C.
  - MacDougall, Malcolm (Box 5)
    "Guess Road Prison Camp." Durham, N.C.
  - Machado, Diane B. (Box 5)
    "White Rock Holiness Church." Durham, N.C.
  - McCartney, Scott (Box 6)
    "Durham Fire Department." Durham, N.C.
  - Moser, Patricia A. (Box 6)
    "Black Muslim School." Durham, N.C.
  - Reed, Nancy (Box 6)
  - Seevak, Alison (Box 6)
    "Oldham Towers." Durham, N.C.
  - Tracy, Ernest B., III (Box 6)
    "Ben H. Williams." Carrboro, N.C.
  - Wang, Caroline (Box 6)
    "Holy Temple of Mount Sinai Church." Durham, N.C.
  - Ward, Eric R. (Box 6)
    "Moreland Avenue/Halley Street." Durham, N.C.
  - Yount, David (Box 6)
    "Sunnyside." Durham, N.C.
- Duke, Spring 1982
  - Callaway, Thomas H. (Box 7)
    "The Rice Dieters." Durham, N.C.
  - Dubilier, Karen (Box 7)
    "Chapel Hill Ballet Company." Chapel Hill, N.C.
  - Glucksman, Jane (Box 7)
    "Durham Nursery School Association." Durham, N.C.
  - Graveen, David, 2 folders (Box 7)
    "Lumbee Indians." Robeson County, N.C.
  - Green, Eric (Box 7)
    "Method Community." Raleigh, N.C.
  - Hoenig, Kathryn (Box 7)
    "The James Family." Durham, N.C.
  - Holch, Meredith E. (Box 7)
    "Fancy Town." Durham and Chapel Hill, N.C."
  - Johnson, Jan Reece (Box 7)
    "Eno River's West Point Community." Durham, N.C.
  - Lyon, Gary P. (Box 7)
    "Fire Station 1." Durham, N.C.
  - Mee, Heather (Box 7)
    "The Wright School." Durham, N.C.
  - Nasser, Sally (Box 8)
    "Johnsie and Clarence Lyons." Durham, N.C.
  - Patterson, Douglas (Box 8)
    "Joseph's Neighborhood." Durham, N.C.
  - Plaut, Christopher R. (Box 8)
  - Raphan, Melissa (Box 8)
    "Hurlburt Family." Durham, N.C.
  - Seward, Alfred Lee, III (Box 8)
    "Nesmith Family." Durham, N.C.
  - Webber, Marsha M. (Box 8)
    "Ranching Communities in the Texas Panhandle." Exact location unknown.
  - Woronov, David (Box 8)
    "Gattis Street/Wilkerson Street/Burch Avenue Community." Durham, N.C.
  - Young, Jennifer (Box 8)
    "Uhlenberg Family." Chapel Hill, N.C.
- UNC, Spring 1982
  - Burniske, Buddy (Box 9)
    "Dan and Hallie Woods." Chapel Hill/Carrboro, N.C.
  - Cates, Diana (Box 9)
    "The Meyers Household." Carrboro, N.C.
  - Crowley, Elizabeth (Box 9)
    "Della Mason." Chapel Hill, N.C.
  - Etherington, Joan Alexander (Box 9)
    "Oyo Tunji." Sheldon, SC
  - Floyd, Bill (Box 9)
    "Strowd Brothers and Sons Dairy Farm." Chapel Hill/Pittsboro, N.C.
  - Gregg, Lauren (Box 9)
    "Cane Creek Community." Cane Creek, N.C.
  - Peel, Sarah Margaret (Box 9)
    "Women in Williamston." Williamston, N.C.
  - Pierce, Penny R. (Box 9)
    "Lumbee Indians." Pembroke, N.C.
  - Post, Susie (Box 9)
    "Purefoy Group Home for Retarded Adults." Chapel Hill, N.C.
  - Reynolds, Amy C. (Box 9)
    "Webster Family." Carrboro, N.C.
  - Salyers, Mary Beth (Box 9)
    "Lakeview Manor Nursing Home." Chapel Hill, N.C.
  - Steacy, Sandra J. (Box 9)
    "Zimmerman Family." Chapel Hill, N.C.
- Duke, Summer 1982
  - Jackson, Donna (Box 10)
    "Sainte-Agnes." Sainte-Agnes, FraN.C.e
  - Mathis, Perry A.and A. Lee Seward (Box 10)
    "Wanchese." Wanchese, N.C. [Eastern N.C.]
  - Mee, Heather (Box 10)
    "Burch Avenue." Durham, N.C.
- Duke, Fall 1982
  - Bowser, David L. (Box 11)
    "609 Wilkerson, 405 Vickers." Durham, N.C.
  - Gans, Kim (Box 11)
    "Life Goes On: J.J. Henderson Housing Center for Senior Citizens." Durham, N.C.
  - Gunnells, Virginia B. (Box 11)
    "Junior Gates--The Glue of a Rural Community." Hillsborough, N.C.
  - Hoenig, Kathryn (Box 11)
    "Durham Academy Middle School." Durham, N.C.
  - Hulme, Leslie (Box 11)
    "A Family of Three." Rougemont, N.C.
  - Kuczynski, Jon (Box 11)
    "Jake's Garage." Durham, N.C.
  - "Chandler's Video" (Box 11)
  - Labalme, Jenny (Box 11)
    "The Warren County PCB Controversy." Warren County, N.C.
  - Lennard, Donna (Box 12)
    "Mr. and Mrs. Chandler - Farmers." Carrboro, N.C.
  - Mathis, Perry (Box 12)
    "The Barringer Family." Hope Valley, N.C.
  - Rich, Robert Jeffrey (Box 12)
    "Lockridge Community." Orange County, N.C.
  - Slaiby, Barbara (Box 12)
    "Sanford Family." Durham, N.C.
  - Strozier, Katherine (Box 12)
    "Durham Care Center." Durham, N.C.
  - Stuart, Susan (Box 12)
  - Ty, Diane (Box 12)
    "Berkeley Street." Durham, N.C.
- UNC, Fall 1982
  - Aquino, Elizabeth (Box 13)
    "Chapel Hill Family." Chapel Hill, N.C.
  - Callum, Gaston Ward (Box 13)
    "Country Farm." Durham, N.C.
  - Collier, David (Box 13)
    "Chi Psi Fraternity." Chapel Hill, N.C.
  - Hahn, Elizabeth (Box 13)
    "Miss Ethel." Durham County, N.C.
  - Hackney, Louise A. (Box 13)
    "Chapel Hill Couple." Chapel Hill, N.C.
  - Huls, Robert B. (Box 13)
    "The Hawkins Family." Durham, N.C.
  - Murphy, Mary (Box 13)
    "Piedmont Heights Mill Village." Burlington, N.C.
  - Powers, Luke A. (Box 13)
    "Brentwood Cottage - The Murdoch Center." Butner, N.C.
  - Wall, Christopher (Box 13)
    "A Southern Urban Family." Durham, N.C.
- Duke, Spring 1983
  - Abell, Marcelle (Box 14)
    "The Durham Male Halfway House." Durham, N.C.
  - Campbell, Elizabeth L. (Box 14)
    "Lion's Club Industries for the Blind." Durham, N.C.
  - Gunnells, Virginia B. (Box 14)
    "Dan River Mills." Danville, VA
  - Hart, Kevin S. (Box 14)
    "The Governor Morehead School." Raleigh, N.C.
  - Jacobs, Wendy (Box 14)
    "Couch's Kwik-Kar Wash." Durham, N.C.
  - Lennard, Donna (Box 14)
    "The Ivy Room." Durham, N.C.
  - Litvack, Jennie (Box 14)
    "Employees of Duke University Food Services." Durham, N.C.
  - Mathis, Perry (Box 14)
    Fuqua School of Business." Durham, N.C.
  - Mitchell, Lauren (Box 14)
    "Excelsior Barber Shop." Durham, N.C.
  - Murphy, Mary (Box 15)
    "Barber Shop and Tailor Shop." Burlington, N.C.
  - Rhone, Llevelyn (Box 15)
    "Men at Work - Durham Sanitation Workers." Durham, N.C.
  - Rich, Robert Jeffrey (Box 15)
    "The Artists and Craftsmen of Lockridge Community." Orange County, N.C.
  - Scriven, Lansing C. (Box 15)
    "Durham Police and Fire Department." Durham, N.C.
  - Seevak, Alison (Box 15)
    "Atlantic Beauty College." Durham, N.C.
  - Slaiby, Barbara E. (Box 15)
    "Cornwallis Road Animal Hospital." Durham, N.C.
  - Trice, Raymond E., Jr. (Box 15)
    "Duke Football, Spring Semester 1983." Durham, N.C.
- Duke, Spring 1983
  - Brook, Roger (Box 16)
    "Firemen of Durham Station 2." Durham, N.C.
  - Cross, Gregory H., Jr. (Box 16)
    "McKinnon Familiy - Primitive Street." Durham, N.C.
  - Demarest, Barbara. (Box 16)
    "Little Friend, Big Friend" Greensboro, N.C.
  - Dunkel, Gail (Box 16)
    "The Kamiyas." Durham, N.C.
  - Epstein, Robin (Box 16)
    "Sally Baker and Friends." Durham, N.C.
  - Evans, Robert Middleton, Jr. (Box 16)
    "A Bahama Family." Bahama N.C.
  - Gordon, Dana J. (Box 17)
    "William 'Fats' Parker and Troy Gentry." Rougemont, N.C.
  - Guthery, B. Katie (Box 17)
    "Kings Daughters Home." Durham, N.C.
  - Jennings, Carol S. (Box 17)
    "The Byrd Family." Durham, N.C.
  - Jordan, John M., Jr. (Box 17)
    "Saxapahaw: Ernest Cagle." Saxapahaw, N.C.
  - Keagy, Laura Ann (Box 17)
    "James." Durham, N.C.
  - Mankoff, Doug (Box 17)
    "North Mangum Street." Durham, N.C.
  - McAllister, Laura E. (Box 17)
    "Eckerd's Lunch Counter." Durham, N.C.
  - Palay, David (Box 17)
    "The Tilley Family." Durham, N.C.
  - Quarfordt, Sharon L. (Box 17)
    "The Brown Family." Orange County, N.C.
  - Tyler, Virginia L. (Box 17)
    "Mentally Retarded Adults in Durham Group Homes." Durham, N.C.
- Duke, Summer 1983 and Fall 1983
  - Labalme, Jenny (Box 18)
    "Coal Miners in Clintwood, VA." Clintwood, VA
  - Rhodenbaugh, Kate (Box 18)
    "Laid-off Steelworkers." Youngstown, OH.
  - Seevak, Alison (Box 18)
    "Shutdown of Butte's Copper Mines - Two Views." Butte, MT
  - Dewey, Paul C. (Box 18)
    "A Gay Couple." Durham, N.C.
  - Durrah, Tracy L. (Box 18)
    "The Shakur's." Durham, N.C.
  - Geehr, Susan B. (Box 18)
    "Yates Baptist Day Care Center." Durham, N.C.
  - Lehr, Victoria (Box 18)
    "Vito Dibona." Durham, N.C.
  - Lowe, Elizabeth (Box 18)
    "Edgemont Park." Durham, N.C.
  - Maass, Harold (Box 18)
    "The Scarborough Nursery." Durham, N.C.
  - Meister, Nancy (Box 19)
    "Temple Beth-El." Durham, N.C.
  - Miller, Beth (Box 19)
    "Hopkins Street." Durham, N.C.
  - Pardoe, Liz (Box 19)
    "Education 242: Group Counseling." Durham, N.C.
  - Phillips, George J. (Box 19)
    "Johnny's County Store." Durham, N.C.
  - Sapp, Jamie (Box 19)
    "An American Familiy." Durham, N.C.
  - Werman, Marco W. (Box 19)
    "A Durham Family." Durham, N.C.
- Summer Projects
  - Green, Eric (Box 20)
    "The Bar AM." Bar AM, Israel.
  - Klausner, Andrea B. (Box 20)
    "Boston School of Ballet." Boston, MA
  - Markwordt, Joe (Box 20)
    "Eastwood Community." Baltimore, Md.
  - Nasser, Sally S. (Box 20)
    "Migrant Farmworkers." Dunn, N.C.
  - Rhodenbaugh, Kate, 2 Boxes (Box 20)
    "North Tennessee Mountains." Campbell and Claiborn Counties, Tenn.
    "Appalachia: Friends." Campbell and Claiborn Counties, Tenn.
  - Wang, Caroline (Box 20)
    "New York City, Chinatown." New York, NY
  - Weenan, Hugo (Box 20)
    "Randall Lanier's Farm." Hot Springs, N.C.
- Duke, Spring 1984
  - Alfandre, Joanne (Box 21)
    "Friends at the School of Science and Mathematics." Durham, N.C.
  - Beazley, Brent William (Box 21)
    "John Umstead Hospital." Butner, N.C.
  - Blalock, Lisa M. (Box 21)
    "Two Rural Families." Durham, N.C.
  - Brawley, R. Hunt (Box 21)
    "1214 Clarendon Family." Durham, N.C.
  - Bradshaw, Suzi (Box 21)
    "Scattered Sites Public Housing." Durham, N.C.
  - Carmen, Kent B. del (Box 21)
    "Nicholas McCrea." Durham, N.C.
  - Chandler, Robert J. (Box 21)
    "Bud's Family." Durham, N.C.
  - Deane, Walter L. (Box 21)
    "The Ellis Family." Bahama, N.C.
  - Getson, Howard M. (Box 21)
    "The Spellman Family." Durham, N.C.
  - Jones, Margaret K. (Box 21)
    "A Community in Transition." Durham, N.C.
  - Jue, Susan L. (Box 21)
    "The Hunam Restaurant." Durham, N.C.
  - Kinkade, Sheila (Box 22)
    "The Marsh Family." Bahama, N.C.
  - Layle, Tristan (Box 22)
    "Being Old and Alone in America." Durham, N.C.
  - Rathert, Robert J. (Box 22)
    "The Survivors." Durham, N.C.
  - Roeckelein, Katrina (Box 22)
    "A Glimpse of Life At McDougald Terrace." Durham, N.C.
  - Ross, Margot (Box 22)
    "Life in a Mobile Home." Durham, N.C.
  - Shreffler, David K. (Box 22)
    "John Avery Boy's Club." Durham, N.C.
  - Siegel, Michael (Box 22)
    "Damar Court Apartments." Durham, N.C.
  - Wells, Karen D. (Box 22)
    "Taylor Seafood." Durham, N.C.
  - Young, Katherine B. (Box 22)
    "Theatre and Children." Durham, N.C.
- Duke, Spring 1985
  - Bailleux, Nicole (Box 23)
    "Oxford Orphanage." Durham, N.C.
  - Bosch, Greg (Box 23)
    "Lamaze Birth and Delivery." Durham, N.C.
  - Buell, H. Burling (Box 23)
    "The Crossroads Farm." Durham, N.C.
  - Cho, Sandy (Box 23)
    "Parker's Restaurant." Durham, N.C.
  - Cilenti, Dorothy (Box 23)
    "Along the Border - Virgilina, Virginia." Virgilina, VA
  - Forsyth, Carol (Box 23)
  - Hanfling, Dan (Box 23)
    "Greensboro Civil Rights Fund." Greensboro/ Durham/ Winston Salem, N.C.
  - Kairys, Lauren (Box 23)
    "Durham Academy." Durham, N.C.
  - Kottler, Laura (Box 23)
    "A Group of Hare Krishnas in Hillsborough." Hillsborough, N.C.
  - Lewis, Ginny (Box 24)
    "The Durham Exchange Club Industries." Durham, N.C.
  - Lynch, Lucy (Box 24)
    "Eckerd's Drug Store." Durham, N.C.
  - Paro, Kathy (Box 24)
    "Delta Delta Delta House." Chapel Hill, N.C.
  - Percival, Robert W. and Landau, Melissa B. (Box 24)
    "Butner Department of Corrections." Butner, N.C.
  - Schneider, Lisa (Box 24)
    "Ninth Street Fire Department." Durham, N.C.
  - Sweeney, Erin (Box 24)
    "The African-American Dance Ensemble." Durham, N.C.
  - Ward, Amy E. (Box 24)
    "B-Bar Stables." Durham, N.C.
  - Werner, Ursula (Box 24)
    "Fishermen in Wrightsville Beach ." Wrightsville Beach, N.C.
  - Wilson, Anne L. (Box 24)
    "Carolina Friends' School." Durham, N.C.
- Duke, Spring 1987
  - Cates, Eddy (Box 25)
    "The Ninth Street Bakery." Durham, N.C.
  - Dirlik, Kira (Box 25)
    "Chuck Davis and the` African-American Dance Community." Durham, N.C.
  - Gesoff, Rochelle Leanne (Box 25)
    "Raleigh Flea Market." Raleigh, N.C.
  - Hunter, Susan J. (Box 25)
  - Hurley, Jim (Box 25)
    "Jordan Ward." Durham, N.C.
  - Lacy, Elizabeth (Box 25)
    "Duke Kitchen Workers." Durham, N.C.
  - Landis, Andrew (Box 25)
    "The Company of 'A Month of Sundays.'" Durham, N.C.
  - Maroldy, Denise (Box 25)
    "Urban Ministries Soup Kitchen." Durham, N.C.
  - Martin, Ann (Box 25)
    "The Durham Bulls." Durham, N.C.
  - Mintz, Louis Neil (Box 25)